Guide to the Charles DeWitt Watts Papers, 1917-2004 and undated RL.01352
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Charles DeWitt Watts papers
1917-2004 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Watts, Charles DeWitt
RL.01352
13.6 Linear Feet
Pioneering African American surgeon who was chief of surgery at Lincoln Hospital, clinical professor of surgery at Duke University, founder of Licoln Community Health Center, director of student health at North Carolina Central University, and vice president and medical director for North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company, all in Durham, N.C. Spanning the period of 1917 to 2004, the Charles DeWitt Watts Papers contain files related to Watts's education, family, community activities, centered in Durham, N.C., and his career as a surgeon, administrator, and trustee on several boards. There is material on the formation in 1901 of Lincoln Hospital, a medical care facility for African Americans in Durham, N.C.. and other items on the early 20th century history of Durham, but the bulk of the papers relate to the later half of the 20th century. Formats primarily consist of correspondence, reports, notes, speeches, photographs, and print materials. It is organized into the following series: Community Relations, Personal Files, Photographic Materials, and Professional Files. Material in the Medical Records Series have been separated and are currently closed to use. Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture.
Approximately 7249 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted. Medical records are currently closed to use.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Charles DeWitt Watts Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2005, 2008, and 2013.
Biographical and Historical Note
Born in Atlanta, Georgia on September 21, 1917, Charles DeWitt Watts was a pioneering African American surgeon. Watts graduated from Morehouse College with a degree in mathematics in 1938. He received his medical degree in 1943 from Howard University College of Medicine in Washington, D.C., where he was mentored by Dr. Charles R. Drew, a pioneer of blood collection and plasma processing. Watts completed his surgical training at Freedman's Hospital in Washington, D.C. from 1943-1948 and worked at Howard as instructor of surgery and director of the cancer clinic from 1948-1949.
In 1945, Watts married Constance Merrick Watts, the granddaughter of North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company founders, John Merrick and Dr. A.M. Moore. They had four children. In 1950, the Watts family returned to Constance's hometown of Durham, North Carolina, where Watts set up a private practice and joined the staff of Lincoln Hospital. He was the first African American to be certified by a surgical specialty board in North Carolina. During his medical career, he served as Director of Student Health at North Carolina Central University (1952-1960), Chief of Surgery at Lincoln Hospital (1965-1976), Attending Surgeon at Watts Hospital (1968-1976) and Durham County General Hospital (1976-1987), and Adjunct Clinical Professor of Surgery at Duke. He retired from private practice in 1988 but continued to consult and teach.
Watts worked for civil rights and quality medical care for Durham residents. He was one of the founders and served on the Board of Durham County General Hospital (now Durham Regional Hospital), the first desegregated hospital in Durham. When Lincoln Hospital closed its doors after the opening of Durham Regional, Watts was instrumental in turning it into the Lincoln Community Health Center, an outpatient clinic dedicated to serving Durham residents regardless of income; he served as its first Medical Director for a year until Dr. Evie Schmidt was hired as its permanent head. Watts also served as Vice-President and Medical Director of the North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company from 1960-1988. From 1978-1993, he was a trustee of Howard University, where he oversaw the university's medical enterprise and engineered the Board's governance reform. In 2002, Duke University Medical School created the Charles Watts Travel Award to help fund faculty and student travel to study culturally specific issues. Charles DeWitt Watts passed away in Durham on July 12, 2004 at the age of 86.
Collection Overview
Spanning the dates 1917 to 2004, the Charles DeWitt Watts Papers contain files related to Watts's education, family, community activities, centered in Durham, N.C., and his career as a surgeon, administrator, and trustee on several boards. The bulk of the material dates from 1970 to 2000. The collection primarily consists of correspondence, reports, notes, speeches, photographs, and print materials, and is organized into the following series: Community Relations, Personal Files, Photographic Materials, and Professional Files. Material containing personally-identifiable medical information in the Medical Records Series has been separated from the other professional files and is currently closed to use.
Largest in the collection is the Professional Files Series, which primarily contains administrative documents related to Watts's career as a doctor, surgeon, and medical administrator for various private practices, hospitals, boards, and professional societies. Of particular note are files related to Watt's mentor, Dr. Charles Drew, the history of Lincoln Hospital, and the establishment of the Lincoln Community Health Center in 1970. The folders in the Medical Records Series have been segregated and are currently closed to use. The Community Relations Series concerns Watts's professional life outside of medicine, containing files related to his membership in churches and fraternal organizations, non-medically-related boards on which he served, his work with Durham, N.C. organizations, his interest in race relations, and honors awarded him. Also included are the papers of Constance Watts (wife), Lyda Merrick (mother-in-law), and Margaret Smith (a nurse in his office). Of special interest is a scrapbook about the Negro Braille Magazine (now the Merrick-Washington Magazine for the Blind), founded by Mrs. Merrick.
Some professional correspondence is also intermixed in the Personal Files Series, which contains papers related to Watts's family, friends, finances, education, and alumni activities. Of particular note is a transcript of Watts's oral history. Containing both professional and personal content, the Photographic Materials Series contains photographs, slides, and negatives. The bulk consists of portraits and snapshots of the Watts family. Of particular note are early photographs of Lincoln Hospital nursing students and staff members.
Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture.
Conditions Governing Access note
Collection has been screened for medical records and other potentially sensitive materials. However, there may be other information protected by privacy laws. Medical records have been segregated and are currently closed to use.
Related Material
Lincoln Hospital Records,
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company Archives,
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Scrapbooks; Blind, Periodicals for the; Health care reform -- United States; African Americans -- Medical care -- History; African American surgeons; Minorities -- Medical care -- North Carolina -- History -- 20th century; Durham (N.C.) -- History -- 20th century; Hospitals -- North Carolina -- Durham -- History; Health facilities -- North Carolina -- Durham; Slides (photographs); Durham (N.C.) -- Race relations -- 20th century; Photographs; North Carolina -- Race relations; Lincoln Hospital (Durham, N.C.) -- History; Merrick, Lyda; Howard University Medical Alumni Association, Inc.; Howard University. Board of Trustees; Drew, Charles Richard, 1904-1950; Duke University. Medical Center -- History; Watts, Charles DeWitt; Watts, Constance Merrick; Watts, Charles DeWitt; North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company; Sigma Pi Phi
- Community Relations Series, 1948-2004, 4 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains papers related to Watts's membership in churches and fraternal organizations, non-medically-related boards on which he served, his work with Durham, N.C. organizations, his interest in race relations, and honors awarded to him. Materials include photographs, correspondence, notes, programs, speeches, programs, clippings, print materials, and a commemorative plaque. Also included are the papers of Constance Watts (wife), Lyda Merrick (mother-in-law), and Margaret Smith (a nurse in his office). Of special interest are materials related to the Negro Braille Magazine (now the Merrick-Washington Magazine for the Blind), founded by Mrs. Merrick. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Alpha Tau Boulé, Sigma Pi Phi, 1969-1982, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - African Methodist Episcopal church, 1978 (Box 1)
  - African Methodist Episcopal Church Review article on Watts, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Charles D. Watts Award, 2001 May (Box 1)
  - City of Medicine Award, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Duke University honors, 1991-2002 (Box 1)
  - Moore Award, 2002 (Box 1)
  - St. Paul's College honorary degree, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Shaw University Award for Outstanding Community Leadership, 1991 Nov. 21 (Box 1)
  - Black colleges, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
  - Chi Delta Mu, 1962-1968 (Box 1)
  - Daughters of Dorcus Club, 1992 Sept. 12 (Box 1)
  - Durham Council on Human Relations, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Durham schools report, 1980 Feb. (Box 1)
  - First Congregational Church, Atlanta GA, 1985-1994 (Box 1)
  - Hayti Development Corporation, 1985 (Box 1)
  - John Avery Boys and Girls Club, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Charles, 1997 (Box 1)
  - A Matter of Law: A Memoir of Struggle in the Cause of Equal Rights manuscript by Robert L. Carter, 2004, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - McKissick, Floyd, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Miller, Helen S., 1982 (Box 2)
  - Minority Community Resources Conference, 1958 Jan. 15 (Box 2)
  - NAACP, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - NAACP, 2000 Oct. 28 (Box 2)
  - National Association of Urban Bankers oratorical competition, 1997 (Box 2)
  - The Negro and the Poor in America materials sent by The North Carolina Fund, 1968 (Box 2)
  - North Carolina School of Science and Math, 1995-2001 (Box 2)
  - Palmer Memorial Institute, 1953 June (Box 2)
  - Palmer Memorial Institute, 1965-1968, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Papers of Merrick, Lyda (Box 2A)
    - Daughters of Dorcus, 1948-1949 (Box 2A)
    - Merrick-Washington Magazine for the Blind, 1987 June (Box 2A)
    - Negro Braille Magazine correspondence and clippings, 1976-1981 (Box 2A)
    - North Carolina Federation of Women's Clubs, 1970-1984 (Box 2A)
    - Photographs, clippings, and correspondence, 1948-1985 (Box 2A)
  - Papers of Smith, Margaret (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 3)
    - Nurse practitioner program, 1977-1979 (Box 3)
    - United Holy Church, 1977-1982 (Box 3)
    - Young People's Holy Association Union, 1974-1979, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Papers of Watts, Constance
    - Durham-Orange County Medical Auxiliary Historical Committee, 1978 (Box 3)
    - United Fund budget book, 1966, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Up the Hill, Jack & Jill of America, Inc., nos. 15-17, 1962-1964, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Premedical Education for Negroes, Charles W. Buggs, 1949 (Box 4)
  - Prison health care, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Race relations articles, 1989-2000 (Box 4)
  - Rotary Club introduction of Josephine Dobbs Clement, c. 1990 (Box 4)
  - Rotary Club pamphlets, 1969-1973 (Box 4)
  - Rotary Club scholarships, 1992-1995 (Box 4)
  - Sanders, Charles, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Seattle Urban League materials, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Southeast Durham Recreation and Youth Activities, 1972 Aug. (Box 4)
  - United Negro College Fund, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Young Black Males in Jeopardy report, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Lyda Merrick scrapbook, 1954-1981 (Box OV1)
  - Calendar of African American History, The Power Within: The Legacy of Dr. Daniel Hale Williams, 1993 (Box OV2)
  - Merrick-Washington Magazine for the Blind, 1989 Dec. (Box OV2)
  - Scrapbook for Alpha Phi Alpha Award of Honor to Dr. Clyde Donnell, 1960 (Box OV2)
- Personal Files Series, 1938-2003 and undated, 3 boxes
  Houses papers related to Watts's family, friends, finances, education, and alumni activities, in the form of correspondence, clippings, memorabilia, speeches, programs, memorial pamphlets, photographs, and oral history transcripts. Some professional correspondence is also intermixed. Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Appointment letters, certificates, awards, educational records, and clippings, 1939-1996, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Armstrong, Wiley Thurber (Dr.), 1981 (Box 4)
  - Biographical sketch, awards, family, 1974-1996 (Box 4)
  - Bruce, William Jr. (Dr.), 2001 (Box 4)
  - Clement, Kenneth W. (Dr.) and Dolores, 1974, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Clement, William A. and Josephine, 1985-2001 (Box 4)
  - Clippings, correspondence, CVs, 1978-2003, 7 folders (Box 4)
  - Clippings, wedding and memorial pamphlets, lists, 1978-1999 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, speeches, certificates, 1952-1982, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Curry, Charles L. (Dr.), 1994-1999 (Box 5)
  - Daniel, John T. (Dr.), 1989 (Box 5)
  - Deerfield Academy, 1971-1973 (Box 5)
  - Donnell, Clyde (Dr.), 1994 (Box 5)
  - Estate planning, undated (Box 5)
  - 50th anniversary, awards, genealogy research, 1985-1997 (Box 5)
  - Gipson, Bernard F. Sr. (Dr.), 1982 (Box 5)
  - Glenview Memorial Park, Inc. financial statements, 1969-1979 (Box 5)
  - Hawes, Ernest, 1983-1985 (Box 5)
  - Hawes and Spaulding families, 1987-2001 (Box 5)
  - Hemphill, Wini Watts, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Hill, Deborah Chase Watts, 1971-1993 (Box 5)
  - Hill, Shana Blake, 1996-1999 (Box 5)
  - Howard alumni materials, 1950-2003, 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Howard Alumni Achievement Award, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Howard Charter Day, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Interview transcript, undated (Box 6)
  - Interview for Black Health Manpower, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Johnson-Thompson, Marian C. (Dr.), 1987-1998 (Box 6)
  - McDougald, Richard Lewis, 1944 (Box 6)
  - Merrick, Constance, 1939 (Box 6)
  - Merrick family history, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Merrick heirs property tax, 2003 (Box 6)
  - Merrick/Moore families cemetery lots, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Moore, Aaron McDuffie (Dr.), 1980, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Moore, Cottie S., 1950 (Box 6)
  - Morehouse alumni materials, 1951-2002, 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Morehouse commencement program, 1938 (Box 6)
  - Morehouse School of Medicine catalog, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Morehouse Triangle Club, 1988-1993 (Box 6)
  - Morehouse yearbook, 1938 (Box 6)
  - Mother of the Year, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Passport, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Rental properties, 1976-2001, 3 folders (Box 7A)
  - Retirement notebook, 1987-1991 (Box 7A)
  - Reunion and commencement programs, 1978-1987 (Box 7A)
  - Schiebel, H. Max (Dr.), 1999 (Box 7A)
  - Smith, Annick, 1963-1977 (Box 7A)
  - Southview Cemetery Association, 1992-1993 (Box 7A)
  - Southview Cemetery financials, 1977 June 30 (Box 7A)
  - Speeches, 1986-1992 and undated, 2 folders (Box 7A)
  - Spellman College, 1988 (Box 7A)
  - Sullivan, Louis (Dr.), 1995 (Box 7A)
  - Trip notes, 1983 (Box 7A)
  - Watts, Albert H., 1977-2002, 2 folders (Box 7A)
  - Watts, Carrie E., 1987 (Box 7A)
  - Watts, Charles DeWitt Jr., 1973-1994 (Box 7A)
  - Watts, Lewis G., 1964 (Box 7A)
  - Welch, C. Eileen Watts, 1990-1996 (Box 7A)
  - Yancy, Asa G. (Dr.), 1990 (Box 7A)
  - Family trip scrapbook, 1957-1962 (Box OV3)
    Contains memorabilia, photographs, and negatives from a Watts family cross-country trip.
- Photographic Materials Series, 1917-2004 and undated, 1 box
  Contains prints, slides, and negatives related to Watts's personal and professional life. The bulk of the material are portraits and snapshots of the Watts, Merrick, and Moore families. Of particular note are early photographs of Lincoln Hospital nursing students and staff members. Additional photographs are located in the Community Relations and Personal Files series. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Daughters of Dorcus, YWCA, c. 1965 (Box 7A)
  - Drew, Charles (Dr.), undated, 2 folders (Box 7A)
  - Events and family, 1992 (Box 7A)
  - Lincoln Hospital, c. 1910?-1945 (Box 7A)
  - Lincoln Hospital history slides, undated (Box 7A)
  - North Carolina Mutual, 1960-2004 (Box 7B)
  - Teaching slides, undated (Box 7B)
  - Watts, Merrick, and Moore families, 1917-1945 (Box 7B)
  - Watts family, 1945-1970 (Box 7B)
  - Watts family, 1970-2004 (Box 7B)
  - E.R. Merrick portrait, c. 1930 (Box OV2)
  - Watts family portrait, c. 1963 (Box OV2)
- Professional Files Series, 1945-2003 and undated, 12 boxes
  Contains files related to Watts's career as a doctor, surgeon, and medical administrator for various private practices, hospitals, boards, and professional societies. Topics include minority healthcare, minority physicians, healthcare cost containment, national health insurance, substance abuse, and child sexual abuse. Of particular note are files related to the history of Lincoln Hospital, the establishment of the Lincoln Clinic, and to Watts's mentor, Dr. Charles Drew. Materials include budgets, planning documents, correspondence, reports, memos, pamphlets, meeting materials, printed materials, policies, grant proposals, event programs, financial statements, CVs, and notes on medical procedures. Files are grouped by the following topics and then arranged chronologically: Durham County General Hospital, Howard University, Lincoln Hospital/Clinic, North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Co., and Professional Societies and Task Forces. Files that fall outside of these groupings are arranged alphabetically at the end of the series. Some additional professional files can be found in the Personal Files Series.
  - Durham County General Hospital (Box 8)
    - Relationship with Lincoln Clinic, grants, long-range planning, 1973-1975 (Box 8)
    - Hunter, David P., 1975 (Box 8)
    - Duke Affiliation Committee, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Medical staff bylaws, safety manual, 1978-1979 (Box 8)
    - Department of Surgery memos, 1978-1979 (Box 8)
    - Bulletin, 1981 (Box 8)
    - Policies, reports, and memos, 1981-1983 (Box 8)
    - Moore, Donald T., 1991 (Box 8)
    - Associated Health Services, Inc., 1994 (Box 8)
    - Health care report, undated (Box 8)
  - Howard University
    - HMO research, memos, progress reports, 1974-1976 (Box 8)
    - Mutual of Omaha policy, 1975 (Box 8)
    - College of Medicine Report, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Board of Trustees, Hospital Advisory Board, 1975-1979 (Box 8)
    - Board of Trustees, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Toward Equal Educational Opportunity: Affirmative Admissions Programs at Law and Medical Schools, 1978 June (Box 8)
    - Syphax, Burke (Dr.), 1978-1995 (Box 8)
    - Pamphlets, 1980-1986 (Box 8)
    - Annual report, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Cobb, William Montague (Dr.), 1984 (Box 9)
    - Presidential Search Committee, 1989-1991 (Box 9)
    - Student Affairs Committee, 1990 Sept. 21 (Box 9)
    - Letters to Dr. Russell Miller, 1991-1992 (Box 9)
    - Hospital Board, 1992 (Box 9)
    - Medical Association meeting, 1993 (Box 9)
    - Board meetings, 1993 (Box 9)
    - Caspa Harris v. Howard University, 1996 (Box 9)
    - Self-Study Report, 1999 Feb. (Box 9)
    - Statement to U.S. House of Representatives, 2000 Mar. 16 (Box 9)
    - Howard University Medical Alumni Association Executive Board meetings, 2001-2003, 6 folders (Box 9)
  - Lincoln Hospital and Lincoln Clinic (Box 10)
    - Postgraduate Clinic Symposia, 1953-1956 (Box 10)
    - Study Committee, 1956 (Box 10)
    - School of Nursing, 1956-1977, 1989, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Staff, 1960-1964 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1960-1968 (Box 10)
    - Housing project, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Health center project, 1963-1977 (Box 10)
    - Reports, proposals, minutes, 1965-1968 (Box 10)
    - History, 1965-1999, with copy of 1899 letter, 7 folders (Box 10)
    - Trustee materials, correspondence, clippings, 1966-1968, 2 folders (Box 10A)
    - Community health center proposal, 1970, 2 folders (Box 10A)
    - Planning, correspondence, 1970-1980 (Box 11)
    - Board minutes, reports, correspondence, 1971-1977, 1994 (Box 11)
    - Progress report, 1972 (Box 11)
    - Reports, memos, schedules, 1973-1979, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Annual public meeting, 1975 Apr. 13 (Box 11)
    - Z. Smith Reynolds Foundation, 1980 (Box 11)
    - Lincoln Apartments financial reports, 1982-1990, 1999-2003, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Report by Rudolph S. Jackson, 1986 (Box 11)
    - Grant support, 1987 (Box 11)
    - Hospital governing board conference 1989 July 15 (Box 11)
    - Continuation request, 1993 (Box 11)
    - Board materials, lease, bylaws, speech, 1994 (Box 11)
  - North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Co. (Box 12)
    - Pamphlets, 1958 and undated (Box 12)
    - The Weekly Review, 1960 Jan. 15 (Box 12)
    - Report on kidney disease, 1970 (Box 12)
    - Clippings, correspondence, speeches, event programs, 1966-2000, 5 folders (Box 12)
    - Financial reports, minutes, evaluations, 1974-1975 (Box 12)
    - Substance abuse research, 1974-1980, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Atlanta University Center, 1978 (Box 12)
    - Wheeler, John Hervey, 1978 Oct. 28 (Box 12)
    - Life Insurers Conference response to Elizabeth Laporte Report, 1979 Mar. 9 (Box 12)
    - Speeches, North Carolina Mutual history, reports, 1983-1988, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Spaulding, Asa T., 1986 (Box 12)
    - Medical Department, 1985-1987, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Smoking cessation project, 1985-1998, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Founders Day, 1987-1996, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - The Whetstone, 1986, 1988, 1997 (Box 13)
    - Board materials, 1990-1996, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Luncheon for Dr. Kenneth Olden, 1991 Oct. 23 (Box 13)
    - Massey invitation, 2000-2001 (Box 13)
    - Congressional Black Caucus, undated (Box 13)
  - Professional Societies and Task Forces
    - Alpha Omega Alpha, 1983-1984, 2003 (Box 13)
    - American Cancer Society, 1993 (Box 13)
    - American Board of Surgery, 1949-1965 (Box 13)
    - American College of Surgeons, 1954-2002, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - American Medical Association, 1976-1983, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - American Society for Microbiology, 1998 May 18 (Box 14)
    - Directories and rosters, c. 1976 (Box 14)
    - Durham Academy of Medicine, Dentistry, and Pharmacy, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Durham-Orange County Medical Society, 1974-1984, 4 folders (Box 14)
    - Institute of Medicine, 1978-2003, 4 folders (Box 14)
    - HMO Task Force, 1974-1976 (Box 14)
    - Healthcare cost materials, 1979-1986, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - National Medical Association, 1977-1991, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - North Carolina Central University Nursing Program Advisory Board, 1984-1992, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - North Carolina Health Insurance Advisory Board, 1963-1979, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - North Carolina Medical Society, 1975-1990, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Medicaid Cost Containment Commission, 1977-1978 (Box 15)
    - Minority Cancer Control Research Advisory Board, 1991 (Box 15)
    - Old North State Medical Society, 1960-1988, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Society of Black Academic Surgeons, 1989-1991, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Triangle Hospice Steering Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 16)
    - UNC School of Public Health Board of Advisors, 1986-1987, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Other Professional Files